JIAN CLARICE P. MERCADO

HUMAN RESOURCE AND PROJECT MANAGEMENT

Ajman, United Arab Emirates | jianclarice@gmail.com | +971522924608

PERSONAL SUMMARY

Accomplished HR professional with a demonstrated history of working, leading, and developing HR Teams to provide full comprehensive HR support services to the organization. Certified Human Resource Professional skilled in Employee Relations, Employee Engagement, HRMS Implementation, Talent Acquisition, and Occupational Safety & Health & Communications as well as Compliance to government requirements in the Philippines and UAE. Experience of working in the Banking, Financial, IT and Software, and e-Commerce industry.

CORE COMPETENCIES

- Program Management
- Employee Relations Events
- Labor Management
- Budget planning & Variances
- Recruitment & Sourcing
- HR Operations

- Management Planning & Organization
- Project Management
- Leadership Skills
- HRMS Project Implementation
- Strong verbal & written communication Skills
- Advance Microsoft Excel, Word, Powerpoint, & JIRA

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Nathan IT Infrastructure, Dubai, United Arab Emirates | Feb 2023 - Present

• HR Functional Consultant

- o Manage and provide solutions to clients related to their HRMS system implementation.
- Successfully implemented over 10 client systems, managing between 5-8 on-going projects simultaneously along with handling accounts of all completed implementations.
- Develop project plans, timelines, and milestones in collaboration with the Project manager.
- Work closely with Developers and QA Team to ensure successful delivery of system.
- o Track and communicate project progress, milestones, and deliverables to stakeholders.
- Perform quality checks on project deliverables to ensure they meet established criteria and standards.
- o Serve as a point of contact for project-related inquiries and provide timely responses to stakeholders.
- o Train clients and end users on system functionality.

Maskany Portal, Dubai, United Arab Emirates | Jun 2021 – Dec 2022

Human Resource Manager

- \circ Led new talent acquisition and recruitment processes for over 10 new full-time hires.
- o Administered company-wide compensation and benefits plans.
- Developed and implemented policies, procedures, and systems, across the organization.
- o Conducted employee on-boarding and organized 5 training and development programs.
- Collaborated with leadership on recruitment strategies, development plans, performance management, and employee engagement programs.
- Assigned to handle the business operations of the company including:
 - Managing 4 full-time employees doing marketing and business development roles
 - 2. Co-authored the company's mission, vision, and core values
 - 3. Implemented process improvement initiatives for database management and reporting
 - 4. Streamlined processes for Merchant Acquiring business

Metropolitan Bank & Trust Company, Taquiq, Philippines | Jan 2020 - Feb 2021

HR Assistant Manager – Occupational Safety & Health | Jun 2020 – Feb 2021

- o Program Manager to the company's telemedicine, employee care, and operational readiness program to provide a continuum of care to employees in the time of the pandemic.
- Planned and implemented 6 initiatives in the current Telemedicine Program which resulted to more effective and efficient report analysis.
- Acted as Training Facilitator for Pollutions Control Officer for 3 months and implemented 3 training programs for over 100 employees.

Created more than 15 databases for Covid Management and Occupational Safety & Health Programs

• HR Assistant Manager – Employee Engagement | Jan 2020 – Jun 2020

- Organized and executed Employee Engagement, Internal Communications, and Corporate Social Responsibility (CSR) programs.
- Created and managed HR communication channels and people-related communication campaigns to ensure organizational awareness

Metrobank Card Corporation, Makati, Philippines | Mar 2012 - Dec 2019

• Employee Relations Officer | Apr 2017 - Dec 2019

- Implemented an online approval and release of employee engagement funds which resulted to production cost savings of 20% and efficiency and accuracy of request of 92%.
- Organized and executed company-wide employee engagement activities, increasing the overall Engagement score of the organization up to 86%.
- Handled end-to-end processing of minor and assigned major cases (preparation of admin memos, issuance to the concerned unit and record-keeping in ER database and filing in 201).
- Prepared and recommended HR budget and reconciled variances which resulted to being awarded as one of the best Cost Champions of the organization for 2 consecutive years.
- Conducted Employee Engagement Module in the New Hires Training and Labor Management 101 to Line Managers
- Conducted exit interviews, composed analysis, and recommended courses of action to minimize employee turnover which led to the organization's turnover percentage below industry average.

Employee Relations Specialist | Apr 2015 – Apr 2017

- Awarded for Performance Excellence Q4 2015 Masters Awardee
- Co-managed and provided recommendations in the conceptualization of ER programs and events.
- Partnered with 7 companies to offer corporate discounts exclusive to the employees as part of employee perks
- Written over 20 articles for publication in the company's intranet related to the company's engagement programs.
- Sourced and successfully recruited 5 customer service representatives for the company.
- Coordinated the end-to-end processing of employee offenses (preparation of admin memos, issuance to concerned unit, record-keeping in database, and filing in 201

Employee Relations Associate | Mar 2012 – Apr 2015

- o Assisted in the execution of approved ER programs and initiatives of the organization.
- Maintained and updated information database concerning ER cases such as disciplinary actions taken against violators, employee exit monitoring, etc., and engagement activities such as FGDs, interviews, project reports.
- Monitored adherence to turn-around times (TATs) and handled documentation of minutes of discussions and audio/phone/video graphic recordings

EDUCATION

Master's in Business Administration

De La Salle University, Manila, Philippines | Jan 2016 - Apr 2018

 Successfully defended the Management Action Research entitled "Implementing a Process for Timely Approval and Release of Employee Engagement Funds at Metrobank Card Corporation"

BSBA Human Resource Development Management

Assumption College, San Lorenzo, Makati, Philippines | Jun 2008 - Mar 2012

- Graduated with Distinction, Leadership and Departmental Award
- Awarded for Best Thesis entitled, "Implementing Organization Development Programs for BPO Company"

CERTIFICATIONS / OTHER COURSES

Certified Human Resource Professional | Credential ID CHRMP2210611451

American Certification Institute | May 2021

Trainer's Certification Bootcamp

Philippine Society for Talent Development, Philippines | August 2019

Recruiting, Hiring, and Onboarding Employees (Online Certificate Course)

Coursera | University of Minnesota | April 2019